# David Ross Dyer

Web Dev / UX / eComm

david@dyer.design https://dyer.design https://linkedin.com/in/mrdavidrdyer 213.864.0129

Hello - My name is David Dyer. I am an artist, skateboarder, music label co-founder, and eCommerce professional; making great strides toward a career in UX Design & Frontend Web Development. Newly certified in both UX and Full Stack, coupled with over a decade in eCommerce Management, makes my skillset and perspective unique. Get in touch and let's build something cool!

# Work Experience

## UX/UI Design Intern - Pepper Square | 2021 - Bengaluru (Remote)

https://dyer.design/pepper-square

- Developed proposals for both web and mobile applications to a range of in-house, client-side projects.
- Crafted rapid prototype demos to present user flow and micro-interactions.
- Provided illustrations to support published articles and case study content.

### Freelance UX Designer - 530 Media Lab | 2020 – 2021 - Long Beach (Remote)

https://dyer.design/vinyl-visions

- Designed the Color Selector & Profile Selector mobile applications -c/o Vinyl Visions; a leading supplier of vinyl door & window trim.
- Eliminated need to annually manufacture/distribute swatch booklets and product catalogs.

# Operations Specialist / Oaklandish | 2018 – 2020 – Oakland

https://dyer.design/oaklandish

- Directed enhanced end-to-end eComm ops for this prominent, Bay-Area apparel brand; housing up to 7 in-house or 3PL product lines simultaneously.
- Independently published/merchandised all web shops, handling fulfillment, logistics, and CRM for each brand through a streamlined, omni-channel approach.

#### eComm Sales Manager / The Hundreds | 2009 – 2017 - Los Angeles

https://dyer.design/the-hundreds

- Spearheaded online sales activity for this quintessential, lifestyle-apparel brand; publishing all collections/collaborations, in-tandem with the launch and analysis of digital marketing campaigns.
- Hired, trained, and managed team of up to a dozen members, while scaling processing yield nearly 400%.
- Executed multiple dashboard migrations, platform integrations, and site redesigns; serving as executive liaison to development agencies.

# Creative Director / Prestige Music Group | 2007 – Present – Atlanta

https://dyer.design/prestige-music-group

- Impassioned director of established record label featuring music catalogs distributed globally in both digital and physical formats.
- Established web presence across key platforms, coupled with a comprehensive rebranding initiative.
- Launched partnership with Triple Vision Record Distribution--Rotterdam, to break into European market.

## **Education**

GA Tech / BootCampSpot – Certified Full Stack Web Development | 2022 – Atlanta

UC / Berkeley Ext. – Professional Certification in User Experience Design | 2020 - San Francisco

**UCF / College of Business Admin.** – B.A. Entrepreneurial Management | 2007 – Orlando / FL Merit Academic Scholarship recipient

Valencia College / A.A. Certified in Digital Video Production | 2004 – Orlando

# **Technical Tools**

Web Dev: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, React, jQuery, Node, Express Session, API design,

MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Insomnia, Heroku, Jest, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwinds,

Agile Methodology, collaborative mindset, and enough git to be dangerous!

Design: Figma, XD, Sketch, Zeplin. Illustrator, Procreate, Premier Pro, InDesign, InVision,

Lightroom, Autodesk, Vectr, CorelDraw, Miro, Lucid Chart

eComm: Shopify Plus, Wix, Magento 2.0, Squarespace, Wordpress, Full Circle, Brightpearl,

Retail Pro, NuOrder, Lightspeed, Blastramp, Mailchimp, Klaviyo, Google Analytics, Salesforce, Constant Contact, Trello, Slack, Cybersource, Authorize, WooCommerce

## **Skills**

Full Stack Web Development / UX-Design / Interface Design / Ideation / Graphic Design / Illustration
Branding / Visual Design / Style Guides / Heuristic Analysis / Typography / Rapid Prototyping / Story Boarding
Wire Framing / User Flows / Diagramming / Usability Testing / User Research / Product Design / Personas
CRM / Digital Marketing / Data Analyst / Logistics / Inventory Audits / Software Integration / Platform
Migration / Team Lead / Critical Thinker / Perfectionist

## **References**

(available per request)

Alka Jha / Senior UX Designer: Pepper Square

Miguel Vazquez / Lead Product Designer: Volkswagen of America Inc.

Kim Dunn / Business Director: 530 Media Lab

Aaron Higgins / Chief Operating Officer: Oaklandish

**Joey Gonzales** / Vice-President: The Hundreds is Huge Inc.

Martijn van Raaij / Head of Digital Distribution: Triple Vision Record Dist.